嘿  怎么了
Hey, what's going on?
我在门上发现张纸条  说"快来莫妮卡家"
I found a note on my door, "Come to Monica's quick.
"带上香槟和三剑客糖[牛奶糖]"
Bring champagne and a Three Musketeers bar."
这是我的
Yeah, I'll take that.
发生什么事了
What's up?
-莫妮卡和我订婚了  -天
- Monica and I are engaged. - Oh, my God.
恭喜  她在哪
Congratulations. Where is she?
我订婚了  我订婚了
I'm engaged! I'm engaged!
她在那喊了20分钟了  你来的路上没听到吗
She's been there for 20 minutes. I'm surprised you didn't hear on the way over?
我还以为是个小孩在喊"我是基友"
I thought it was a kid yelling, "I'm gay!"
-我能把她拉回来吗  -随她去吧  怪甜蜜的
- Can I bring her in? - Let her stay. It's sweet.
我要结婚了  我要做新娘了
I'm getting married! I'm gonna be a bride!
我才不要闭嘴  因为我订婚了
No, I will not shut up, because I'm engaged!
就会说  敢来当面对我说吗
Oh, big talk! Why don't you come here and say that to me?
我未婚夫会把你揍得屁股开花
My fiance will kick your ass.
来啊  20号公寓  20号公寓
Come on, apartment 20, apartment 20.
你拉她进来  你去插门  我去壁橱避风头
You get her in, you bolt the door, I'll be in the closet.
慢着  慢着
Okay, wait, wait, wait.
我只想说  我超爱你们大家  超爱
I just want to say that I love you guys so, so much...
感谢大家和我共度这个对我而言非常特别的夜晚
...and thank you for being here on my special night.
对我们而言非常特别的夜晚
Our special night.
我的这一晚不会如此美妙  我们的这一晚
It just wouldn't be my night... Our night...
如果不是你们在这里和我一同  和我们  该死
...if you weren't here to celebrate with me... us. Damn it!
没事啦  我也希望这是属于你的夜晚
It's okay, I want this to be your night too.
敬莫妮卡
To Monica.
得啦  别这样
Come on, wait, stop it.
好吧  敬莫妮卡
Okay, to Monica.
决定好婚礼要请的乐队了吗  因为
Have you decided on a band for the wedding? Because you know...
我可是个音乐家
I'm kind of musical.
她几小时前才订婚
She got engaged a couple of hours ago,
我想她都没时间想这些
I doubt she's even had time to think...
说到这里不得不提
Speaking of chiming in,
你还记得自己有一次把我公寓烧了吗
remember the time you burned down my apartment?
你自己搞定吧
Yeah, you're on your own.
我们现在应该衣着光鲜  去广场喝香槟
You know what we should do? We should get dressed up and go have champagne at the Plaza.
我待不了太久
I can't stay too long.
得要早起为支广告试镜  良好精神状态很重要
I gotta get up early for a commercial audition. I gotta look good.
要演一个19岁的男孩
I'm supposed to be playing a 19-year-old.
怎么了
What?
你说要早起  是指1986年吗
So when you said get up early, did you mean 1986?
你们不觉得我像19
You guys don't think I look 19?
你是说19  我们以为是90
Oh, 19! We thought you said 90.
好了大家伙儿  走吧
Okay, everybody, let's go.
我剩下的糖在这吗
Is the rest of my candy bar around here?
没啊亲爱的  你自己吃完了
No honey, you ate it all.
就怕这个
I was afraid of that.
你知道什么鞋能配得上这枚戒指吗
You know what shoes would look great with this ring?
钻石鞋
Diamond shoes.
你还不换衣服
You're not getting dressed.
你懂的
Know what I mean?
我懂  但我觉得时间不够啊
Yeah, but I don't think we have time.
我们将有一场盛大的婚礼
There's gonna be a wedding.
你会是新娘
You're gonna be the bride.
200名宾客会见证你穿着美轮美奂婚纱的时刻
200 people are gonna be looking at you in a clean, white dress.
来吧
Let's do it.
钱德勒  很多男人都会有这样的时刻
Chandler, it happens to lots of guys.
你也就是累了  喝了太多香槟
You're tired, you had a lot of champagne.
别担心
Don't worry about it.
我才不担心  我只是觉得这很奇妙
I'm not worried. I'm fascinated.
生物学如此奇妙
You know? It's like biology.
有趣的是  我高中的时候生物挂了科
Which is funny, because in high school I failed biology...
今天晚上生物挂了我
...and tonight biology failed me.
听听  趁着等大家的时候
Check it out. I could play
我弹给你听听  来了
this while the guests are coming in. Okay.
第一次我遇到钱德勒我以为他是基友
First time I met Chandler I thought he was gay
但现在我身处他的婚礼为他放声歌唱
But here I am singing on his wedding day
菲比  不
Phoebe, no.
你要听我唱完嘛
If you'd let me finish,
后面会唱到他也许不是基友
it goes on to say that he's probably not gay.
你们反正没有这种烦恼  你们是木头人
You guys don't have this problem, you're made of wood.
你看上去真美
Hey, you look great.
谢谢
Thanks.
你还好吗
You okay over there?
我也不知道  我有一点
I don't know. You know? I feel a little...
算了  别管了  我会没事的
You know what? Never mind. I'll be fine.
别担心  你也就是累了
Don't worry about it. You're probably tired,
喝了太多香槟
you had a lot of champagne.
人人都有这样的时刻
It happens to everybody.
-莫妮卡之夜快乐  -谢谢你也是
- Happy Monica's Night. - Well, thank you. You too.
你能相信吗  他们真的要结婚了
Can you believe this? Can you believe they are actually getting married?
是挺难以置信的  但我一直也都在结婚
Well, sure, but I get married all the time.
-你还好吗  -大概吧
- You okay? - Yeah, I guess.
你觉得我们会有那么一天吗
Do you think we'll ever have that?
你是说"我们"  你和我
You mean "We," you and me?
不不不
Oh, no, no, no.
"我们"是指  你和某人  我和某人
"We," you with someone, me with someone.
好  你吓着我了
Good, you scared me a minute.
我知道  别担心
I know. Shake it off.
只是因为你和我  我们俩在一起就像是噩梦
It's just because you and I, we were like a nightmare.
但是还是有美好时光的
No, but there were some good times.
当然了  就好像
Absolutely. Like, there was...
-你肯定能想起些美好片段的  -给我点时间
- Surely you can think of something. - Just give me a minute.
好吧  对了
Oh, well, yes.
我可以想到一件美好的事情
I can think of one good thing.
你很擅长于
You were always good at the...
那些事情
...stuff.
我很擅长于那些事情
I was good at the stuff?
我很喜欢你的双手
I really liked your hands.
手
My hands?
干得不错啊  伙计们
Way to go, guys.
你也很擅长于一些事情
You were really good at the stuff too.
我知道
Oh, I know.
你知道我们有什么是没做过的吗
Hey, you know what we never did?
不  不是你想的那个
Oh, no, not that.
我们从没有过"额外一夜"
We never had a bonus night.
-什么  -就"额外一夜"
- A what? - You know, a bonus night.
两人分了手  然后来个一夜风流
Two people break up, but they get back together for one night.
就一夜  就嘿咻  没其他附加规则
One night, just sex? No strings attached?
-对  从来没试过  -是啊我们没试过
- Yeah, yeah, we never had that. - No.
这个变得有点疯狂了
Okay, this is getting a little crazy.
我很确定那么一夜一定很美妙
I'm sure it would be amazing...
但我真的不觉得这是个好主意
...but I really don't think it would be a good idea.
我真的
I really...
真的
...really...
不觉得
...don't.
咋样
'Sup?
咋样  伙计
'Sup, dude?
要什么你拿走  别伤害我就行
Take whatever you want, just don't hurt me.
还玩索尼游戏机呢
You playing a little PlayStation, huh?
超逊啊
That's whack.
那游戏机超逊
PlayStation is whack.
咋样外加超逊的游戏机  咋样
'Sup with the whack PlayStation, 'sup?
得了  我是不是十九
Come on, am I 19 or what?
对  从一到十
Yes, on a scale of one to ten,
十是我见过的最弱智的人
ten being the dumbest a person can look...
你绝对有十九
...you are definitely 19.
得了  说真的  多大
Come on, man, really. How old?
幼稚  你就是个外表老成内心幼稚
Young. You're a man-child, okay?
去换衣服  因为大家都准备好了
Now get changed, because everybody's ready.
还有拜托  拜托留着我的内裤吧
And please, please, keep my underwear.
谢谢
Thanks.
你嘿咻了好多次  对吧
You've had a lot of sex, right?
什么时候  今天
When, today?
就几次  没好多次
Some, not a lot.
我问你是因为我有点
The reason I'm asking is because I had kind of a...
我之前有点
I was unable to...
我很想要  但是我就是没办法
I really wanted to, but I couldn't...
别担心  那时常发生
Don't worry about that, man. That happens.
-你有过  -对啊  一次
- It's happened to you? - Yeah, once.
-那你怎么解决的  -死了都要做啊
- Well, what'd you do? - I did it anyway.
菲比  快点  该走了
Phoebe, come on, let's go.
快点
Come on.
你怎么还没换衣服
Why aren't you dressed yet?
抱歉  但我刚刚为你的婚礼写了一首最棒的歌
I'm sorry, but I just wrote the best song for your wedding.
听
Check this out.
如果你现在去换衣服  我就让你在婚礼上唱
If you get ready now, I will let you can play it at the wedding.
-乔  -怎么了
- Joe? - Yeah!
-真的  -真的
- Really?! - Yes.
太好了  谢谢莫
That's so exciting! Thanks, Mon.
但如果你再敢摸我的吉他
But if you touch my guitar again,
我就要小小修理一下你了
I'll have to pound on you a little bit.
行  快去换衣服  我去叫大家
Fair enough. Get ready. I'll get everybody.
我们终于可以开始庆祝我的
Finally we can start celebrating my...
抱歉  很明显我打开了通往过去的门
I'm sorry, apparently I opened the door to the past.
莫妮卡  亲爱的  你刚刚看到的
Okay, Monica, Mon. Okay, what you just saw...
我能问你个小问题吗  为什么一定得在今天晚上
Can I ask you just a little question? Why tonight?
-什么  -我等着订婚已经等了一辈子
- What? - I've been waiting for my whole life to be engaged...
不像某些人  我只打算结一次婚
...and unlike some, I only plan on doing this once.
也许我太自私了  对不起
So you know, maybe it's selfish, I'm sorry.
但我希望今晚能只属于我
But I hoped tonight could just be about that.
亲爱的  今夜就是只属于你的
Oh honey, but it is just about that.
现在这是你的复合之夜了
Now it's about you and Ross getting back together.
看  你们有点喧宾夺主了
See, you kind of stole my thunder.
我们没有喧宾夺主  因为我们没有复合
We did not steal your thunder. Because we are not getting back together.
对  我们没有  而且都没人看见
Yeah, no, and you know what? Nobody even saw.
也对
That's true.
-我们就是接吻而已  -就是一个吻
- We just kissed. - It was just a kiss.
你们接吻了
You guys kissed?!
代表着什么
What does this mean?!
你们复合了吗  我能在你们婚礼上献唱吗
Are you back together? Can I sing at your wedding?
喧宾夺主了
Thunder being stolen.
-菲比  那不算什么  -别大惊小怪的
- Phoebe, it's nothing. - Let's not make a big deal of this.
就只是一瞬而过  不作数的
It was a one-time thing. It doesn't even matter.
天啊
Oh, my God.
我简直不敢相信你们居然在讨论这个
I cannot believe you guys are talking about this.
闺房秘事应该在两人之间解决
Problems in the bedroom are between a man and a woman.
钱德勒已经尽力了
All right? Now, Chandler is doing the best he can.
我不觉得他们在讨论这个
I don't think that's what they were talking about, Joe.
多美好的一夜啊  钱德勒不举  他们接吻
What a great night. Chandler can't do it, they kissed.
-什么  -你们接吻了  这可是大事
- What? - You guys kissed? This is huge.
不  不是大事
No, it's not huge.
你们都大惊小怪  这让莫妮卡觉得
People thinking it's huge has led Monica to believe...
我们喧宾夺主了  我们才没有
...we're stealing her thunder, which we aren't.
我们还在聊这个  不是吗
We're still talking about it, aren't we?
那可不是钱德勒的错
That ain't Chandler's problem.
莫妮卡  听我说
Monica, listen, listen.
如果我们不再讨论
Would you feel better
瑞秋和罗斯的事  会不会让你好受一点
if we stopped talking about Ross and Rachel?
-那样就好了  -没问题
- That would be lovely. - You got it.
我绝对能演十九岁的  对吧
Now, I can pass for 19, right?
对  你绝对能演十九岁的
Yes, you can pass for 19.
-真的吗  -对
- Really? - Yes.
-认真的吗  -要听真心话
- Seriously? - Seriously?
真心话就是  不行你只能演你自己年龄  31岁
Seriously, no. Okay? You can play your own age, which is 31.
我才30
I'm 30!
乔伊  你不是  你31了
Joey, you are not. You're 31.
糟糕
Oh, crap!
去广场吧  吃泰国菜如何
So the Plaza. We'll get some Mai Tais?
你就不应该再吃辣了
Maybe no more for you though.
我不想去广场了
You know, I think I don't feel like going to the Plaza.
莫妮卡  这太荒谬了
Monica, this is ridiculous.
我不想谈  特别是和你
I don't want to talk about it. I don't. Especially with you.
太逊了
That is whack.
我要在婚礼上演奏
I'll play it at the wedding.
到时候再看吧
We'll see if they actually let you play.
他们总是先说些你喜欢听的
They tell you anything you want to hear...
就好像"你看上去像19岁"
...like, "You look 19."
然后他们再夺走这一切  说"其实没有"
Then they just take it away, like, "No, you don't."
莫妮卡不会这么对我的
Monica won't take this away.
-她不会吗  -她会吗
- Wouldn't she? - Would she?
她会吗
Would she?
猜猜是谁
Guess who.
我们还有些悬而未决的事情
Hey, I just realized we kind of left some stuff up in the air.
莫妮卡说
What did Monica mean by
"我不想谈"  特别是和我  是什么意思
"I don't want to talk," especially with me?
为什么不是你和我  我们俩都在接吻
Why not especially you and me? We were both out there kissing.
还想这个呢
Still thinking about it?
我认真的  她说"特别是你"是什么意思
I'm serious. What did she mean by that? "Especially you."
-谁在乎啊  -我在乎
- Who cares? - I care.
我也在乎
And so do I.
我必须得和她谈谈  你能让我把衣服换了吗
I have to talk to her. Will you let me get changed?
我邀你观赏我更衣了吗
Am I going to let you watch me undressed?
没
No.
简直不敢相信  她这太明显了
I can't believe her. It's just so typical.
我知道你生气
I know you're upset,
但别忘了  你还会有婚礼
but don't forget there is going to be a wedding.
你要扔花球  还有蜜月呢
You are going to throw the bouquet, and then a honeymoon.
-也许去巴黎  -巴黎
- Maybe in Paris. - Paris?
我们也许会在啥啥啥大道上月下漫步
We will take a moonlit walk on the Rue de la blah-blah-blah.
继续说
Keep talking.
我们可以在洒满玫瑰花瓣的大床上做爱
We will sprinkle rose petals on the bed and make love...
不仅是因为这很浪漫  更因为我能
...not just because it's romantic, but because I can.
我爱你
I love you.
你好  先生
Bonjour monsieur.
什么都别说  把小兄弟吓跑了就不好了
Don't say anything, you might scare it away.
这可是巴黎  谁知道我们在巴黎
It's Paris. Who knows we're here?
菲比  怎么了
Hi, Pheebs. What's up?
你说我能在你婚礼上献唱  我得要点订金
You said I could sing at your wedding, so I need a small deposit.
给点小钱  让我好空出档期
You know, some good-faith money to hold the date.
我才不要给你订金
We're not giving you a deposit for our wedding.
我懂了
Oh, I see.
他们伤了你的心  对吧
They break your heart, don't they?
我不需要他们的同意
You know, I don't really need their permission.
你想在他们婚礼上唱歌  就去吧
You want to sing at their wedding, sing at their wedding.
如果你想看起来像19岁  你就
Yeah, and if you want to look 19, then you...
你得整一下你的眼睛
You got to do something about your eyes.
我的眼睛怎么了
What's wrong with my eyes?
它们出卖了你  太智慧
They give you away. There's too much wisdom in there.
拿茶袋敷15分钟
Put some tea bags on them for 15 minutes.
-茶袋会掩盖我的智慧吗  -敷十分钟就好
- That'll get rid of my wisdom. - Maybe 10 minutes for you.
把订金给她  戒指也给她  我不在乎
Give her the deposit, give her the ring. I don't care.
-什么事  -你什么意思  当你说
-Yes? -Monica,what did you mean when you said...
你不想谈  特别是和我
...you didn't want to talk to anyone, especially me?
这道歉真棒  而你也接受了  再见
What a great apology. And you accept. Bye-bye.
认真的  那"特别是和我"是为什么
No, seriously, what was the "Especially me" part about?
这不是你第一次喧宾夺主了
Let's just say it's not the first time you've stolen my thunder.
我这么想
Hey, here's a thought...
莫妮卡  你说什么呢
Monica, what are you talking about?
我16岁生日  你和我表哥上了三垒
My sweet 16. You went to third base with my cousin Charlie.
三垒啊
Third base.
每个人都在讨论这事儿
It was all everybody could talk about.
我那么做只不过因为你的派对太无聊了
Monica, you know what? The only reason I did that was because your party was so boring.
我们请了一个漫画家
We had a caricaturist.
要是我结婚  猜猜谁不会被请来献唱
Whenever I get married Guess who won't be asked to sing
姓盖勒的和姓宾的
Somebody named Geller And somebody else named Bing
莫妮卡  你的16岁生日已经是一百万年以前的事了
Monica, your sweet 16 was like a million years ago.
你今天不是又来了一回吗
Yet here you are doing it again.
我才不想喧宾夺什么主
I don't want to steal your stupid thunder.
那你为什么要和罗斯亲热
Why else would you have made out with Ross?
可是抓住我了
Got me.
别想了  那一瞬的感觉已经没了  不可能了
Easy, Mimey, the moment has passed. It ain't gonna happen.
如果今夜能只属于我  就好了  就这一晚
It'd be nice if I could have just this one night.
我才不想在你的夜晚中分一杯羹
I never wanted any part of your night.
大家都不应该看见我们接吻的
No one was supposed to see us kissing.
所以你们才在僻静的小走道上接吻
Is that why you did it
因为永远都不会有人看见
in the secret hallway, where nobody ever goes?
瑞秋  我一直在考虑
Rachel, I've been thinking.
我不觉得我们俩今晚一夜风流会是个好主意
I don't think us getting together tonight is such a good idea.
我不干了
I'm calling it off.
挽回面子的好方法啊  伙计
Way to save your dignity, my man.
莫妮卡  我为什么会想要喧宾夺主呢
Mon, why, why would I ever want to take away from your night?
也许你就是有点不高兴
I don't know, maybe you feel a little resentful.
也许你以为你会先结婚
Maybe you thought you'd get married first.
也许你就是无法忍受
Maybe you can't stand...
你那个以前很胖的朋友会先结婚
...that your formerly fat friend is getting married before you.
这太不公平了
Oh, wow, that... You know what? That is so unfair.
现在我想要喧宾夺主了
Now I want to steal your thunder.
走罗斯  做爱去
Come on, Ross. Let's go have sex!
我简直不敢相信你们竟然要在我的订婚夜做爱
I can't believe you're gonna have sex on my engagement night.
总得有人做
Well, somebody should.
如果我们要做
Look, if we're gonna do this...
我们没有要做  只是让她以为我们做了
We're not gonna do this. She's just gonna think we are.
好吧  多赢
I see, so everybody wins.
-谁啊  -莫妮卡  开门
- Who is it? - It's Monica, open up.
罗斯  停一下拜托  等一下
Okay, Ross, stop it. Please, wait a minute.
你喜欢这样对吧  宝贝
Yeah, you like that, baby?
我们能帮到你吗
May we help you?
我要告诉你我希望你们俩今晚做爱
I wanted to say I hope you do have sex tonight,
我也希望你们复合
and I hope you get back together.
我警告你  你要宣布订婚当晚
I warn you, the night you announce your engagement...
我要宣布我怀孕了
...l'm going to announce that I'm pregnant.
那怎么可能呢
How is that ever going to happen?
你想知道今晚我为什么会和罗斯在一起吗
Do you want to know why I was with Ross tonight?
-我知道  -你才不
- I know why. - You don't.
-好吧  为什么  -因为我很伤心
- Okay, why? - Because I was sad.
什么意思
What do you mean?
听着  我非常
Look, I am so...
非常为你们高兴
...so happy for you guys.
但你要结婚这件事提醒了我  我没有要结婚
But you getting married reminds me of the fact that I'm not.
我八字还没一撇呢
I'm not even close.
许我只想让自己好过一点
Maybe I just wanted to make myself feel better.
我知道这很蠢  但是罗斯结婚的时候
I know that that's dumb, but you were so depressed...
你太沮丧  以至于跑去和钱德勒睡了
...when Ross got married, you slept with Chandler.
我无所谓  和她睡的是我
I don't care, she slept with me.
甜心  很抱歉我毁了专属你的今晚
Anyway, sweetie, I am so sorry I ruined your night.
我很抱歉让你几乎和罗斯上床
I'm sorry I almost made you sleep with Ross.
我要走了
I'm gonna take off.
-恭喜 -谢谢
- Congratulations, man. - Thanks.
还有瑞秋
And Rachel...
我能说什么呢
...what can I say?
你错过了你的机会
You missed your chance.
从现在起
From now on, the only
能享受这对魔术之手的  就只有我了
person who's gonna enjoy these bad boys is me.
我们以为菲比会离开
We thought Phoebe would leave
但是她却留了下来
But she just stayed and stayed
没错  我彻夜在此
That's right, I'm here all night
钱德勒会永远无法
And Chandler will never get...
给你一美元
Hey, here's a dollar.
就算是订金吧  请在我们婚礼献唱
Consider it a deposit. Please sing at our wedding.
谢谢
Thank you.
谁要在婚礼上献唱
Now who will perform the ceremony
谁要在婚礼上献
Who will perform the cer...
明早再教训他好了
I'll pound on him in the morning.